Previously on Gotham...
Who are those people
you were speaking with?
You keep your nose out of my business.
Now, now, Butch, play nice.
If a person comes into
contact with my blood,
it changes them.
My brother... he gets
in your mind, you're doomed.
Good-bye, Mr. Gordon.
- Ivy's missing.
- She'll turn up somewhere.
This time she fell.
It was a long way down into water.
Maybe she survived.
- What's your name?
- My name's Ivy.
Barnes asked me to put you on
a 48-hour suicide watch. I've
already signed off on it.
- He just cost you the election!
- Give me one reason
why I shouldn't let Butch
kill you where you stand.
- Oswald Cobblepot
- There's that.
Has won the mayor's office.
I believe in you, Oswald.
You never believed
I could win this election on my own.
Maybe you're not cut
out for this, after all.
What?!
- Jervis. Let her go now.
- No!
I'll never go with you!
No!
You killed her!
I would like to introduce you
to my chief of staff,
Mr. Edward Nygma.
Welcome your new mayor of Gotham.
Mayor Oswald Cobblepot.
He'll make Gotham safe again.
Welcome your new mayor of Gotham.
Mayor Oswald Cobblepot.
He'll make Gotham safe again.
Welcome your new mayor of Gotham.
Mayor Oswald Cobblepot.
Thank you so much, thank you.
There's something I've
been wanting to ask you.
Am I a good boy?
Have I made you proud?
I hope I'm not interrupting.
Oh, Ed, you never met my mother.
Wasn't she beautiful?
A fine figure of a woman.
She was my whole world.
The only one that was
always there for me.
Well, I believe the answer is yes.
She would be proud.
Do you really think so?
Oswald, look at everything
you've achieved.
The people love you.
Gangs fear you.
And tomorrow night, the crème of Gotham
will be gathering to celebrate you.
What more could someone ask for?
Someone to share it with.
My mother was the
daughter of immigrants.
A humble cook.
We did not have much,
but when she was by
my side, I felt loved.
Protected.
As promised, I have rid Gotham
of its villainous monsters.
With my mother as my witness,
I vow to you from this day forward,
every man, woman,
and child in our great city
will be safe!
No one is safe. Not from us.
Drop it.
Put it down.
You will pay for this!
Dearly!
Now, now, Mr. Mayor.
Don't go losing your head.
Have a nice day.
- Sync and corrections by madhatters -
- www.addic7ed.com
I can't come over tonight.
Okay.
I mean, that'd be three nights in a row.
That'd almost make it a thing.
The neighbors might talk.
Exactly. And I have a dinner.
It's not a date.
None of my business.
Uh-huh.
So... whatever happened with Tetch?
I told you.
He broke his sister out of the GCPD.
Bullock and I chased him down.
She died. He escaped.
'Cause I heard a rumor
there's something
strange about her blood.
Do you like this?
I think I made that pretty clear.
Then why are you pressing?
Because I want to know.
Are you asking as a
reporter or as yourself?
Is there a difference?
There should be. When you were a cop,
did you stop being one
when you came home?
Maybe that was my problem.
Hmm.
The guy I'm having dinner
with is the hematologist
in charge of analyzing
Alice Tetch's blood.
I'm free after 10:00
if you want to call.
Thanks for the coffee.
We found the truck.
They ditched it in the Narrows.
We got forensics going over it
and teams doing a ten-block sweep.
We already found this.
The Red Hood Gang.
I thought those idiots were dead.
My guess is they're copying the look.
The original Red Hood
Gang were bank robbers.
Whoever they are, they
got a beef with Penguin.
Expand the search to 15 blocks.
Everything goes through you.
You mean through me.
Wow.
It is good to be back.
I have missed all of you.
Harvey.
Still a stranger to a
haircut and a shave, I see.
What are you doing here, Nygma?
As Mayor Cobblepot's chief of staff,
I'm gonna be your liaison on
the Red Hood investigation.
I want to see all reports.
I'm gonna need access
to your forensic lab.
You think I'm gonna just let
you waltz into my precinct?
You're a cop killer who should be
in the loony bin.
- I'll be damned...
- You'll be fired.
The mayor can't fire me.
No, but he can appoint
a police commissioner who will.
So... you will carry out
the mayor's orders without question
or the GCPD has a new captain.
How does that sound?
Every dog has his day, Nygma.
Enjoy yours.
And where is our lord mayor?
Hiding under his desk?
He's meeting with constituents.
"Anything for you, my
little Cobble Pot."
"You can count on me."
Those were the words my
mother used to whisper to me
every night before I fell asleep.
She was a saint.
Yes.
A saint whose only desire was
to love me.
And what was her thanks?
Not only did she take
a knife in the back...
but even in her death, her
memory is being desecrated.
Seriously?
This is the reason we're here?
A little glue.
Some paint.
Mama will be good as new, eh?
No!
That is not the reason you are here.
The Red Hoods have
challenged my authority.
They will be made an example of.
Tonight,
I am celebrating my historic victory...
At the Sirens.
It's gonna be fabulous.
None of you are invited.
I want them found and
their leader's head
brought to me on a
spike before nightfall.
What are you waiting for?!
Find them!
All right, five-card draw, gentlemen.
All right, someone didn't ante up.
Come on, you cheap bastards.
How long are we supposed to wait?
Long as it takes the
boss man to get here.
You need a lookout.
Uh, relax, fellas.
Hey, uh, you want us
to deal you in, boss?
We don't have time for games, boys.
We got work to do.
Hello, Jim.
Is it a bad time? I should've called.
No.
Please, come in.
Can I get you something to drink?
- A... glass of water?
- I'm fine.
I heard you were back.
I've been meaning to come see you.
- Everything okay?
- Yes.
Alfred and I are both well.
I hear you're a private
investigator now.
I'd like to hire you.
Uh, Bruce, if this is about corruption
at Wayne Enterprises... It's not.
I've put my investigation into
my father's company aside.
It's time I moved on.
Why the sudden change of heart?
It's far from sudden.
I've given it a great deal of thought.
I can't live my life
if I keep looking back.
For what it's worth,
I think that's wise.
So, what can I do for you?
Ivy Pepper's gone missing.
I didn't realize you two were close.
We're not, she's a friend of Selina's.
And does Selina know you're doing this?
No.
I don't want to get her hopes
up if we don't find anything.
Well, we'll start with the GCPD.
See where we go from there.
I think it's chivalrous,
you doing this for Selina.
How long have you two been a thing?
Oh, no, no, no.
- Selina's a friend, that's all.
- Mm-hmm. Yeah.
No, really, she's just a friend.
Yeah, yeah.
Mr. Fox,
just the man I've been wanting to see.
Oh, joy. Mr. Nygma.
Heard you were stopping by.
I have questions.
- Hopefully, you have answers.
- Or what?
You'll poison me with gas?
That gas was a sleeping agent.
And to be fair, I was not in
the best place in my life.
To be fair,
if you ever threaten my life
or the life of Bruce Wayne again,
I will find a way to end you.
Mr. Fox, we both know you're
not a man of violence.
No, I am not.
If I was, I would've laced
some piece of lab equipment,
one which you were sure
to touch, with a toxin.
Ricin, maybe.
I'd use Saxitoxin. Harder to trace.
But I like your style.
You are insane.
Was insane.
I have a certificate.
- So, the Red Hoods?
- See for yourself.
The gang's getaway vehicle
was abandoned in the Narrows.
As you'll notice,
its carpet fibers has
elements of dirt, oil,
and, oddly, potassium chloride.
A halide salt.
Fascinating.
So nothing on Ivy Pepper,
but an odd report came
in a few weeks ago, okay?
A construction worker claimed
that a redhead knocked
him out, robbed him,
and she left this.
That's Ivy's sweater.
How do we find this man?
I already called, all
right? The guy's down south
on a job, but he swore up and down
that the redhead who rolled him...
- was in her 20s.
- So?
He's probably covering for
being with a young girl.
Doubtful he would come
forward in the first place.
Yeah, most pervs don't want to
call attention to themselves.
So it wasn't Ivy.
It seems unlikely, but why
would she have Ivy's sweater?
Dr. Thompkins.
Bruce, it's good to see you again.
You got taller.
Like I said, right? The
kid's growing like a weed.
Nice to see you, too.
Uh, Jim, could I have a word?
Wanted you to hear it from me, um,
my engagement announcement is coming out
in The Gazette tomorrow.
And it will feature Mario's name.
I think that's customary.
His family name.
You mean Falcone.
You knew?
You knew and you didn't say anything?
Sure I did.
I said congratulations.
- Don't be cute.
- Lee.
People talk.
Was I surprised? Sure.
But it's also none of my business.
Your life is your life.
And I meant what I said.
Very happy for you.
So, that's it?
That's it.
Okay, um, well, I just...
wanted to tell you.
Dr. Thompkins.
I had heard that you were back.
I'm so glad...
That's for Kristen.
You shouldn't have done that. Or what?
I'm supposed to be scared of you
because you work for Penguin?
My fiancé's father is Carmine Falcone.
I so much as whisper to him,
and you disappear.
Tell the mayor, whatever I can
do as M.E., I'm happy to help.
It's bad enough we're
throwing Penguin's party.
It's good for the club.
Now we're his errand girls?
Sweetie, we find the
Red Hoods, he'll owe us.
We can ask for a favor,
say him not killing you?
Well, it would be nice not
to have to watch my ass
all the time.
Well, well.
Who do we have here?
Guy calls himself the Ballistic Bomber.
My contact at the Merc saw him buying
- smoke grenades last week.
- Ooh.
Just like the ones the
Red Hoods used on Penguin.
Groovy.
Reckon he'll talk?
Of course.
No!
Maybe give him a moment.
Now remember, kids,
you tell the press this
is all Penguin's fault.
- Good.
- Yes, sir.
Light it up.
- Oh, mercy.
- Please. No, no.
Better run, Sister,
'fore the Padre goes boom.
Lord Jesus!
Don't!
Wait, wait! The grenade is slipping!
Seriously, a priest?
You should've seen it.
Ka-boom!
But you told 'em what to say?
- This is all because of Penguin?
- Yeah, boss, but I don't get it.
You want to take out
Penguin, let's take him out.
This Red Hood stuff is fun,
but it's a lot of work.
How about you just do what I tell you?
Now, I got you these
so you'll blend in at the party tonight.
Huh? Huh?
Nice suit.
And that's when we kill him?
No!
No one kills Penguin.
You should.
'Cause he's going to murder you.
Time to have a heart-to-heart, Butch.
Alone.
You don't have to buy lunch.
I know you're a billionaire,
but I can buy you a sandwich.
Do you miss it?
Being a cop?
Sometimes, yeah.
Gave a sense of mission.
True.
There's more to life
than having a mission.
Look, I'll keep asking
around about Ivy, but, uh...
you want my advice,
talk to Selina.
Tell her how you feel.
Does that actually work?
Sometimes.
It's definitely better
than being silent.
Before you know it, the moment passes.
And are you taking your own advice?
Afraid that ship has sailed.
I'm not talking about Dr. Thompkins,
I'm talking about the
woman you're seeing now.
Excuse me?
There was lipstick on a
coffee mug on your table.
You've become quite the detective.
So, are you?
It's complicated.
- So is Selina.
- That I believe.
I just wish sometimes...
I had a sign.
Unfortunately, life doesn't
usually work that way.
We're hours away
from Mayor Cobblepot's
victory celebration.
But people are asking,
will the Red Hood Gang
put a damper on the festivities?
Sounds like Penguin's having a bad day.
I'm supposed to go to his party tonight.
Part of my re-engagement
with being a Wayne.
Mm.
Well, give the mayor my best.
Witnesses say the Red Hoods
blamed Cobblepot for their ac...
Someone is testing me, Ed.
They're thinking, "Oh, he's mayor now.
He has to play by different rules."
No, they'll see,
when I'm roasting their
entrails over a fire.
Perhaps I'm thinking
about this all wrong.
Perhaps this is not about you at all.
What if this is about the statue?
Of course it's about me!
Yes, you're probably right. Oh, dear.
- Wonderful.
- Oswald.
Take a breath.
What are you doing?
It's an old trick I learned in the lab.
Most solvents have as their base...
I am the son of water,
but if water touches me, I die.
- What am I?
- Again with the riddles.
Salt. Most people think
of it as a food additive,
but potassium salt is
found in detergents,
- soaps...
- What is your point, Ed?
I know where the Red Hoods are.
I say we give him to Penguin.
Knowing Penguin will
gut him like a fish.
Ladies, come on.
- After all we've been through...
- It's his life for yours.
Simple.
I don't get it.
Why'd you turn on him now?
I wasn't gonna hurt Penguin.
Honest.
I was gonna take down
the Red Hoods myself.
Tonight. At the party.
All this so you could play the hero?
Ever since Nygma got out of Arkham,
Penguin treats me like I'm nothing.
That pencil-neck's
trying to push me out.
Let me ask you, we
figured out you're the man
behind the Red Hoods, how
long do you think it'll take
Penguin and his lap dog?
It's your life, baby.
You make the call.
Let me see this through.
I get my place beside Penguin back,
I'll protect you.
Oh, you'll do more than that.
You'll owe me.
And one day, I'm gonna collect.
Gilzean.
Butch, where are you?
The Red Hood Gang is
at a detergent factory
in the Narrows. We're on our way.
I got to go.
Get your things.
We're done. I'm breaking up the band.
I'm serious, go! Get out of Dodge.
Yeah, well, not for nothing,
but you promised us a payday.
We're not leaving till we get it.
Well, I guess it was gonna
happen sooner or later.
What?
Sorry, boys.
I did it, boss.
I got 'em for you.
Peace and order have
once again been restored
to Gotham.
The Red Hood Gang is no more.
My very own man, Butch Gilzean,
risked life and limb to
face down the bandits.
Was your life ever in danger, Butch?
I can honestly say that
if I'd have hesitated,
I'd have been a goner.
All right, people, listen up!
It's happy hour...
Finish up those reports
and let's call it a day!
Hey, uh... Ed.
Even before you went crazy,
I never liked you.
Your zipper's down.
Listen, Butch did us all a favor.
Red Hoods go bye-bye, case closed.
Look at the way the bodies fell.
It's as if they were just standing
there, waiting to be killed.
Butch comes all the way in the room,
but only one man pulled out a gun.
I guess they weren't threatened.
By a 300-pound gorilla?
Whose side are you on, anyway, hmm?
No one's losing sleep over
a bunch of dead crooks,
least of all me.
I said wrap it up!
What have we here?
Burning the midnight oil?
I was just finishing up.
I'm guessing you're
here to reprimand me.
Reprimand you? For what?
Punching Nygma in the jaw.
I just couldn't help myself.
First I'm hearing of it.
Well done, Doctor.
Actually, I'm here to ask about, uh...
Alice Tetch's blood, if
you've heard anything.
As it happens, I just received
the preliminary results
back from the lab.
- Fascinating.
- What is?
They injected samples
into a group of rats.
After three days, two of the rats
were showing marked increases
in strength and stamina.
Oh? That doesn't sound so bad.
But the study ended after one of
the rats killed all the others.
I'm guessing that's not normal.
It chewed through a dozen wire cages
to get at them... no.
Well, why would one
of the rats go psycho
and not the others?
Perhaps the others hadn't had a chance
to show any symptoms,
or they were immune.
Some people live with
a disease for years
without having any adverse effects.
The lab is starting a new study now.
Well, keep me informed.
Oh, and, uh... don't stay too late.
I'm sure that fiancé of yours
would like to see you once in a while.
And was the captain of the GCPD invited
to our new mayor's victory party?
You know, I lost my invitation.
I can feel it.
Heard you took down the Red Hood Gang
single-handed.
So to speak.
- Very funny.
- Don't forget,
you owe me.
I know.
How long do we have to stay?
As long as it takes for you to be seen
in the world, Master Bruce...
being Bruce Wayne.
And smiling.
So this is our life now?
Fake smiles and mingling.
I miss the old days.
- So nice.
- Oh, excuse me.
Yes.
Bruce, Mr. Pennyworth,
I'm so pleased you made it.
Yeah, well, you know, we're trying to
get out a bit more, Mr. Mayor.
Oswald, please.
We never got the chance to thank you
for saving our lives from the ex-mayor.
Not at all.
I find it very fortuitous
you turned up when you did
with that bazooka.
I just felt a bit sorry
for Stan, the gardener,
'cause he was picking up
bits of Galavan for weeks.
And now here you are, the new mayor.
Sometimes life has a way of working out.
Yes, that's true.
What is it, Master Bruce?
A sign.
Please excuse me.
Right, well, I'll just
go and wet my beak.
Congratulations again, Mr. Mayor.
- Hey!
- Hey yourself.
Funny, I never realized
how short you were.
Who the hell are you?
Not yet. This is too fun.
Run along, little kitty.
Go steal some more wallets.
Hey.
So sweet.
There he is, the man of the hour.
I have a surprise for you, Butch.
Not in the mood.
What's in the box?
Open it.
Thanks.
- I already got one.
- Oh, of course you do.
And you certainly
wouldn't need this one,
as it's so similar to your
very own pocket square.
This is from the Red Hood crime scene.
It turns out that your suit
and the Red Hood suits were all made
by the same tailor, Mr. Fuji.
That's some coincidence.
I thought so myself.
Which is why I called
Mr. Fuji, and he said
that a large man with a metal hand...
Not many of those running around...
Bought all six of the suits,
which means, ta-da, you're
the architect of the Red...
I should snap your neck right now.
You haven't heard my offer.
We kill Penguin together.
What are you talking about?
- You're his guy.
- Oh, please. You fell for that act?
Yes, he broke me out of Arkham...
Very appreciative...
But I was not cut out to be number two.
I've simply been waiting for my moment,
which you have graciously provided.
How would you like to
run Gotham with me?
The two of us... working together?
You have proven yourself far
more cunning than I imagined.
Now, I assume this little drama of yours
was meant to climax tonight.
So put on the hood, kill Penguin...
I'll help you escape.
Tomorrow we divide up the city.
You'd really turn on him,
after all he did for you?
In a heartbeat.
No.
Okay.
Then I guess it's time
for surprise number two.
- You got to Zsasz?
- I got to Zsasz.
And he got to Tabitha.
Penguin's history.
The question is, are you?
Can I see your invitation?
What are you doing here?
- I was invited.
- Of course you were.
You recognize her?
Should I?
I don't know.
Hey, are you, you...
- I'm me.
- Uh-huh.
Well, I'm working, so...
Actually, there was something
I wanted to tell you.
Could we go somewhere more private?
Fine, but make it quick.
I can't believe you'd
turn on Oswald, too.
Uh, hello. Pot, kettle, black.
No, it's not the same thing. You...
Never mind.
I swear, your goons hurt Tabitha,
so help me...
Just do your job.
Oh...
showtime.
Put on in the mayor
before I put one in Tabitha.
Ladies, gentlemen,
welcome to The Sirens.
Tonight we're here to celebrate
the Honorable Mayor Cobblepot.
Our savior from the monsters,
and the captain of our fair city.
And now, the mayor would
like to say a few words.
Ed, where've you been?
I've been looking for you all evening.
Oh, just tying up loose ends.
I just wanted to say...
good luck.
Okay. Thank you.
Thank you.
Hmm.
Tonight is a celebration,
not of my victory,
but of Gotham's.
This is a new day!
I wouldn't celebrate yet, Mr. Mayor.
Red Hoods ain't finished yet.
Ed!
- What are you doing?!
- Wait!
Sorry, boss.
Butch?!
- Huh?
- Oops.
The mayor...
our mayor... vowed that all
of the Red Hoods would be destroyed.
And now we have the
real leader caught...
red... handed.
You really thought I'd
give you real bullets?
You are an idiot!
I will kill you for this!
Sounds like we're missing all the fun.
Got plenty of fun left for you.
You know, if you're gonna take
a girl hostage in her own place,
you might want to search it first.
After all that I've done for you!
- I gave you a job!
- I gave you everything!
I used to be somebody in this town,
then you and that sniveling
little son of a...
Shut up!
I am shocked...
and grieved...
that one of my dearest
friends has betrayed me.
But let it be known
that Oswald Cobblepot
will prosecute anyone
who threatens Gotham!
Hear, hear!
Yeah!
Upsy-daisy.
Oh, my God.
Showtime.
Oswald, move.
I am gonna enjoy this.
Best... party... ever.
Wait.
- Not now.
- Ed!
Ed!
Oh!
So, what's up?
I hired Jim Gordon to
help me locate Ivy.
And?
There was a redhead
that had her sweater,
but it wasn't Ivy.
Saying it out loud, I realize,
doesn't sound that impressive.
No, it doesn't.
That's really why you
brought me up here?
You are the real Bruce...
'cause nobody else would be this boring.
- Great work, detective.
- That's not all.
We've been friends a long time, Selina.
And ever since you've known me,
I've been dedicated to one thing,
but that's done.
I don't know what's next, but I know...
Would you, please...
just say what you mean?
I like you...
as more than a friend.
It would be nice if you
said something back.
How many girls have you dated?
What do you mean?
It's not a trick question.
How many girls have you dated?
- None.
- None. Hmm.
Have you ever thought that maybe
you only like me because
I'm literally the only girl you know?
That's not true. I feel something.
And I know you do, too. We're the same.
In what universe are we the same?
- The money doesn't matter.
- Try not having it.
It matters.
There's something between us.
I know there is.
You have to see that.
Rule one.
Don't ever tell me
what I have to do.
So, you do have feelings for me?
- I'm confused.
- Good.
Come on, just tell me.
I got all dressed up.
I even put on lipstick.
I could lose my job.
What are you offering?
Fine, then I'll say something.
If I'm right, you just nod.
You ran tests on Alice Tetch's blood.
You found something in her blood.
A virus, or infection or something.
Do I have to go over the rules again?
Let's have new rules, sweetie.
I'll tell you what we're
doing with Alice Tetch's blood
and in return...
you...
O...kay.
Excuse me?
What are you doing?
Two whiskeys and a pineapple
juice for this guy.
What's going on?
- To go.
- What's going on?
I think you were just leaving.
Forget this.
Trust me. I'm gonna try.
What are you doing here?
Just walking by.
Saw you through the window.
- Took it as a sign.
- Like hell.
You tracked me here.
And for the record,
I could've gotten what I wanted
from that creep without
compromising my honor.
I know...
but you don't have to.
I'll tell you what you want to know.
I thought you wanted to keep the
woman and the reporter separate.
- Is that an option?
- No.
Well, then.
You are gonna have to
buy me dinner, though.
What's good here?
It's ginger tea with honey.
It's my mother's remedy
for a sore throat.
You sure you don't need a doctor?
No, I'm fine.
I still don't understand
why you didn't tell me
what you were doing.
Your shock when seeing
Butch had to be genuine.
The people had to believe it...
and they did.
And once again, you're the city's hero.
But you were almost killed.
And you saved me... again.
I hope you know, Oswald...
I would do anything for you.
You can always count on me.
Thank you.
Need a hand, kitten?
I got it.
Hold on, Butch.
Sir, the ambulance carrying
Butch Gilzean was just hijacked.
Damn it!
Put out a BOLO.
I'll call the mayor.
Oh, yes.
M-M-Mister, please.
Shh.
My dear, sweet sister.
Just look...
at what he did to you.
He took you from me!
We belonged... together!
And he killed you.
But, mister, I-I'm not dead.
If only that were true.
Those who hurt you...
will feel my pain...
when my sweet and terrible vengeance
upon them rains.
www.tvsubtitles.net